# This file should contain all the record creation needed to seed the database with its default values.
# The data can then be loaded with the rake db:seed (or created alongside the db with db:setup).
#
# Examples:
#
#   cities = City.create([{ name: 'Chicago' }, { name: 'Copenhagen' }])
#   Mayor.create(name: 'Emanuel', city: cities.first)



User.create([
	{username: "admin", name: "Bryan Knouse", password: "admin", password_confirmation: "admin"}
])

Question.create([
	{question: "Where is NATO headquarters located?", answer_a: "The United States", answer_b: "Latvia", answer_c: "Belgium", answer_d: "France", answer_correct: "answer_c", factoid: "This centrally located headquarters puts it in close proximity to the former battle against communism.", activity: "What does NATO stand for? Read the NATO Treaty dated 1949."},
	{question: "Who was President at the end of World War II?", answer_a: "Franklin Roosevelt", answer_b: "Theodore Roosevelt", answer_c: "Harry Truman", answer_d: "Dwight Eisenhower", answer_correct: "answer_c", factoid: "The US entered WWII after the attacks at Pearl Harbor, Hawaii. This Vice-President assumed the position of President after the death of FDR.", activity: "Under the Constitution, who succeeds the President if he/she should die or become incapacitated?"},
	{question: "What military branches are mentioned in the US Constitution?", answer_a: "Navy and Army", answer_b: "Coast Guard and Air Force", answer_c: "Marines and Air Force", answer_d: "None of the above", answer_correct: "answer_a", factoid: "These two major branches, which are the oldest and largest, are specifically listed in the Constitution.", activity: "What section of the US Constitution mentions these two military branches?"},
	{question: "What was the Missouri Compromise?", answer_a: "An Agreement determining how many votes Missouri should get in Congress", answer_b: "An Agreement between pro-slavery and anti-slavery factions in Congress regulating slavery in western territories", answer_c: "An Agreement between John Adams and Thomas Jefferson over who would govern Missouri", answer_d: "An Agreement between the President and Congress over Missouri statehood", answer_correct: "answer_b", factoid: "This Agreement resulted in the addition of several states under different rules", activity: "Read the Missouri Compromise."},
	{question: "The landmark federal case of Marbury V. Madison established what legal principle?", answer_a: "States can assess income taxes", answer_b: "No state can tax another", answer_c: "The Supreme Court has the right of judicial review", answer_d: "The Supreme Court majority decides the law", answer_correct: "answer_c", factoid: "The right of the Supreme Court is a defining factor in its ability to make legal rulings.", activity: "Learn about the case and understand the Supreme Court’s role under the US Constitution."},
	{question: "The Civil War ended on what date?", answer_a: "4/9/1865", answer_b: "3/1/1863", answer_c: "9/7/1875", answer_d: "12/1/1776", answer_correct: "answer_a", factoid: "The war ended at Appomattox Courthouse several years after the Confederacy seceded from the Union. Confederacy General Robert E. Lee surrendered to Union General Ulysses S. Grant. Appomattox Courthouse is a place in Virginia, not an actual courthouse.", activity: "Look up which States seceded in the 1860s."},
	{question: "What was the process of American reconciliation with the South called after the Civil War?", answer_a: "American Reconciliation", answer_b: "Reconstruction", answer_c: "Resurrection of the South", answer_d: "All for One, One for All", answer_correct: "answer_b", factoid: "Reintegration of the South after the Civil War involved rebuilding relationships and infrastructure. President Lincoln, before he was assassinated, was magnanimous toward the South after the Union was preserved.", activity: "Review which US President led the reintegration of the South after the Civil War."},
	{question: "How many times was Franklin Delano Roosevelt elected President?", answer_a: "2", answer_b: "3", answer_c: "4", answer_d: "1", answer_correct: "answer_c", factoid: "FDR was elected so many times, leading to the two-term limit following his presidency.", activity: "What Constitutional Amendment provides for the two-term Presidential election limit?"},
	{question: "The 5th Amendment to the Constitution provides what protection to all citizens charged with a crime?", answer_a: "The right to a speedy trial", answer_b: "The right against self-incrimination", answer_c: "The right against self-immolation", answer_d: "The right to keep and bear arms", answer_correct: "answer_b", factoid: "Part of your Miranda rights, this is granted in the 5th amendment to the US Constitution.", activity: "Look up who Miranda was."},
	{question: "What percentage of votes does it take for Congress to pass a Constitutional Amendment?", answer_a: "A simple majority of both Houses of Congress", answer_b: "A 2/3 majority of both Houses of Congress", answer_c: "A simple majority of the House and a 2/3 vote of the Senate", answer_d: "A simple majority of the Senate and a 2/3 majority of the House", answer_correct: "answer_b", factoid: "More than a majority vote must occur in Congress to amend the US Constitution.", activity: "Outline the process for amending the US Constitution."},
	{question: "How many state legislatures must ratify a Constitutional Amendment passed by Congress?", answer_a: "A simple majority", answer_b: "A 2/3 majority", answer_c: "A 3/4 majority", answer_d: "A 5/8 majority", answer_correct: "answer_b", factoid: "More than a simple majority must vote to pass a Constitutional Amendment", activity: "Identify when the last Constitutional Amendment was ratified by the states."},
	{question: "What are the duties of the US Supreme Court?", answer_a: "The Court interprets the law under the US Constitution.", answer_b: "The Court makes the law according to state court cases.", answer_c: "The Court conducts trials of federal civil cases only.", answer_d: "The Court conducts only criminal trials relating to federal offenses.", answer_correct: "answer_a", factoid: "The Supreme Court does not make laws.", activity: "Look up the section of the US Constitution that identifies the Court’s role."},
	{question: "Which President initially deployed troops to Vietnam?", answer_a: "Lyndon B. Johnson", answer_b: "John F. Kennedy", answer_c: "Richard M. Nixon", answer_d: "Dwight D. Eisenhower", answer_correct: "answer_a", factoid: "JFK’s successor, President Lyndon B. Johnson, first committed troops to Vietnam, though President Kennedy sent some 16,000 “military advisers” to Vietnam before he was assassinated in 1963.", activity: "What did former President Dwight D. Eisenhower advise JFK about American troops in Vietnam?"},
	{question: "Which President created the US Environmental Protection Agency?", answer_a: "Jimmy Carter", answer_b: "Theodore Roosevelt", answer_c: "Richard M. Nixon", answer_d: "John F. Kennedy", answer_correct: "answer_c", factoid: "President Nixon, a Republican, created the EPA.", activity: "Identify the EPA’s latest administrative action."},
	{question: "What do the letters IMF stand for?", answer_a: "International Manufacturers of Finance", answer_b: "International Marketing Futures", answer_c: "International Monetary Fund", answer_d: "International Marketing for Farmers", answer_correct: "answer_c", factoid: "The IMF is an economic fail-safe for many developing nations.", activity: "Who decides who receives IMF funding?"},
	{question: "What foreign country received the most US aid in 2012?", answer_a: "Afghanistan", answer_b: "Canada", answer_c: "Egypt", answer_d: "Israel", answer_correct: "answer_a", factoid: "It receives massive aid as part of redevelopment and military assistance totaling nearly $13 trillion in 2012.", activity: "Identify the total amount of foreign aid that comes from the US government."},
	{question: "What is the approximate amount of current US debt?", answer_a: "$30 trillion", answer_b: "$18 trillion", answer_c: "$5 trillion", answer_d: "$500 billion", answer_correct: "answer_b", factoid: "The current national debt is approaching the current gross domestic product, a dangerous economic equation.", activity: "Identify how much interest is paid each day to service the national debt."},
	{question: "What is the projected US federal budget deficit for 2016?", answer_a: "$474 billion", answer_b: "$50.3 trillion", answer_c: "$6.78 billion", answer_d: "$3.67 trillion", answer_correct: "answer_a", factoid: "For the fiscal year 2016 (October 1, 2015-September 30, 2016) the federal budget deficit is projected to be at its lowest level since it was $1.4 trillion in 2009.", activity: "Track the level of federal spending and federal deficit from 2000 to 2015."},
	{question: "How is the Speaker of the US House of Representatives chosen?", answer_a: "By Presidential appointment", answer_b: "By election of House Members", answer_c: "By election of House and Senate Members", answer_d: "By Senate ratification", answer_correct: "By election of House Members", factoid: "The Speaker is chosen by election at the beginning of each new two-year Congress. House members orally register their vote.", activity: "Research whether any prior House Speaker has ever NOT been a House Member."},
	{question: "What is the highest rate of federal individual income tax in the US?", answer_a: "10%", answer_b: "39.6%", answer_c: "35%", answer_d: "15%", answer_correct: "answer_b", factoid: "This tax rate applies to very few high income individuals since most pay less due to deductions and other tax shelters, though most high income individuals pay a very high percentage of all income tax collected by the IRS.", activity: "Identify the percentages of taxation and what percentages of Americans are included under each bracket."},
])

